Guide to the Duke University Libraries Collection of Haggadot, 1200-2003 (bulk1900-2003) RL.00491
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Location List Series, 1200-2003
  For countries that have changed names and for which Duke has Haggadot during times when the country had a different name, the modern name of the country is used. For example, there is a Haggadah from Tel Aviv (Haggadah Pam #7) which was printed prior to the creation of Israel in 1948, when the country was called Palestine. Since Tel Aviv presently lies within the borders of Israel, Haggadah Pam #7 is found in the Israel Subseries.
  Countries represented in this series include Algeria, Argentina, Austria, Bosnia-Hercegovina, Canada, Czech Republic, England, France, Germany, India, Israel, Italy, Morocco, Netherlands, Poland, Portugal, Russia, Spain, Tunisia, and United States. Each individual Haggadah's description identifies the publication city if it is known.
  - Algeria Subseries, 1889-1890, 1 item
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1889-1890., Illustrated; 18 cm
  - Argentina Subseries, 1949, 1 item
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / [edited by] Pablo Link, 1949., Illustrated; 21 cm
      Hebrew and Spanish with ceremonial directions, notes and introduction in Spanish.
  - Austria Subseries, 1851-1922, 4 items
    - Hagadah = Racconto degli avvenimenti memorabili occasionanti la Pasqua / traduzione riveduta e corretta dall' Mayer Randegger, 1851., Text only; 21 cm
      Contains the traditional Hebrew text with an Italian translation. Handwritten notes appear throughout in Hebrew (Rashi script), Italian, and Greek Four handwritten pages, In Hebrew and Italian, were inserted into the beginning of the Haggadah. These pages serve as an annotated table of contents. Signed on the inside of the cover.
    - Hebrew title romanized. | Cover title: Hagadah shel Pesah = Hagadah for Passover, 1921., Illustrated; 22 cm
      Edited and printed by Union (Appel Brothers)
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah: ...mit sipurim oyf `Ivri Taytsh, 1921., Illustrated; 22 cm
      Commentary by Jacob ben Wolf Kranz (1740?-1804), who is also known as the Dubnow or Dubner Maggid.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Seder service Hagadah for Passover / ... meturgam `al yede Rahel Me'ir .., 1922., Illustrated; 21 cm
  - Bosnia-Hercegovina Subseries, 1983, 1 Item
    - The Sarajevo Haggadah / Eugen Werber; [translation, Olga Popovic-Marjanovic], 1983., Text only; 23 cm
  - Canada Subseries, 1999, 1 Item
    - Like an orange on a Seder plate: our lesbian Haggadah / Ruth Simkin, 1999., Illustrated; 21 cm
  - Czech Republic Subseries, 1526-1900, 7 Items
    - Die Pessach-Haggadah des Gerschom Kohen, 1527 [i.e. 1526], 1526., Illustrated; 32 cm
      Reproduction of the Frankfurter Stadtbibliothek copy of the original ed., printed by Gershom ben Solomon ha-Kohen, in Prague in 1526. This reproduction was printed in Berlin, Germany in 1926.
    - The earliest illustrated Haggadah: printed by Gershom Cohen at Prague / discovered and described by Lazarus Goldschmidt, 1526., Illuminated; 29 cm
      Reproduction was published in 1940 in London, England. Translated from the German manuscript by Immanuel Goldschmidt.
    - The Passover Haggadah of Gershom Cohen: printed at Prague, in the year 5287/1527, 1526., Illuminated; 18 cm
      Facsimile reproduction was published in 1954 in Tel Aviv, Israel. Includes an introduction in English. This Haggadah is the oldest known Haggadah to be printed with woodcuts. These woodcuts would go on to be the source for woodcuts used in many other printed Haggadot. Unique to this Haggadah is the mention of an obscure practice. On p. 36 is a woodcut of a man holding a leaf of lettuce and pointing to it with a note that It is generally customary that the husband points to his wife because of the Biblical reference that a bad woman is more bitter than death.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1526., Illustrated; 36 cm
      Facsimile was printed in New York, 1964. Includes an English introduction.
    - The earliest illustrated Haggadah: printed by Gershom Cohen at Prague / discovered and described by Lazarus Goldschmidt, 1526., Illuminated; 29 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Prag 287 = The Passover Haggadah: Prague 1526, 1526., Illustrated; 32 cm
      Facsimile was printed in Jerusalem in 1972.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah = Hagada: Gebete für den häuslichen Gottesdienst am ersten und zweiten Abende des Pessachfestes / Deutsch übersetzt und erlautert von Dr. R.T. Fürstenthal; nebst einem Gedichte "Das Pessachfest" von Salomon Plessner, 1900., Illustrated; 18 cm
  - England Subseries, 1779-2003, 24 items
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1779-1780., Illustrated; 17 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah = Service for the two first nights of Passover: in Hebrew and English, according to the custom of the German and Polish Jews / carefully revised and corrected by Isaac Levi .., 1842., Illuminated; 21 cm
      Contains 8 copper plates relating to the service.
    - The Haggadah according to the rite of Yemen: together with the Arabic-Hebrew commentary / published for the first time from mss. of Yemen with an introduction, translation and critical and philological notes by William H. Greenburg, 1896., Text only; 23 cm
    - The Haggadah according to the rite of Yemen: together with the Arabic-Hebrew commentary / published for the first time from mss. of Yemen with an introduction, translation and critical and philological notes by William H. Greenburg, 1896., Text only; 23 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1897., Text only; 23 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1930., Illustrated; 32 cm
    - The Haggadah: a new edition / with English translation, introduction, and notes by Cecil Roth; with drawings by Donia Nachshen, 1934., Illustrated; 25 cm
      Second title page claims that it was printed in Holland.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Passover Hagadah: services for the Passover nights / arranged by H. Meiliz; with illustrations, 1937., Illustrated; 18 cm
    - Seder Hagadah le-lel shimurim = Hagadah service for the first two nights of Passover / with a revised English translation of the text of the Rev. A.P. Mendes, 1940., Illustrated; 22 cm
    - Hagadah Bet Ya`akov / leha-gaon ha-kadosh Ya`akov `Emden.; y.l. `im ha-hosafot me-R. Mosheh Shov, 1942-1943., Text only; 24 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1946., Text only; 19 cm
    - Passover Haggadah / edited by Lazarus Goldschmidt; illustrations by Bruno Frost; translation by Paul Goodman, 1946., Illustrated; 29 cm
      English and Hebrew. Includes song for unacc. voice: Had gadya.
    - [Hagadah li-yeladim] = The children's Haggadah / edited by Dr. A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Ersin Singer; with a new translation in prose and verse by Mr. Isidore Wartski ... and Rev. Arthur Saul Super M.A.; and with a selection of Seder melodies, 1948., Illustrated; 30 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = The Passover Haggadah / with a new English translation by Isidore Fishman .., 1951., Text only; 21 cm
    - The John Rylands Haggadah / Cecil Roth, 1960., Resource Material; 25 cm
    - Hagadah li-yeladim = The children's Haggadah / edited by A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Erwin Singer; with a new translation in prose and verse by Isidore Wartski and Arthur Saul Super; and with a selection of Seder melodies, 1963., Illustrated; 30 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = 4th-World Haggadah: with commentary / compiled by Joel Harris; edited and new English translation by Jack Schuldenfrei, 1970., Illustrated; 23 cm
    - Hagadah li-yeladim = The children's Haggadah / edited by A.M. Silbermann; illustrated by Erwin Singer with a new translation in prose and verse by Isidore Wartski and Rev. Saul Super, 1972., Illustrated; 29 cm
    - Passover Hagadah / illustrated with the commentary of Rabbi Dr. Marcus Lehmann of Mainz, rendered into English for the first time, 1975., Illustrated; 26 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = 4th-World Haggadah: with commentary / compiled by Joel Harris; edited and new English translation by Jack Schuldenfrei, 197-?., Illustrated; 23 cm
    - Hagadat Betsal'el: Hagadah shel Pesah / ma`aseh yede Mati Grinberg, 1984., Illustrated; 55 cm
    - The animated Haggadah [videorecording], 1985., Video.
    - The Golden Haggadah / Bezalel Narkiss, 1997., Illustrated; 30 cm
    - The Chief Rabbi's Haggadah: Hebrew and English text with new essays and commentary / by Jonathan Sacks; [English Haggadah translation [by] Shlomo Riskin], 2003., Text only; 24 cm
  - France Subseries, 1925-1964, 4 items
    - Haggada de Pessah / texte hébreu revu par le rabbin Back; mis en français par Edmond Fleg; orné d'illustrations de Janine Aghion, 1925., Illustrated; 28 cm
      Hebrew with a French translation Limited ed. of 1500 copies on rag paper.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1939., Illustrated; 19 cm
    - The Pessach Haggadah = Hagadah shel Pesah, 1964., Illustrated; 21 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / he`etik u-tsayar Benyamin Sha'n; `im targum, mavo, u-he'arot me-et Betsalel Rot, 1966., .; 40 cm
  - Germany Subseries, 1200-=1954, 30 items
    - The Birds Head Haggada of the Bezalel National Art Museum in Jerusalem / Facsimile volume printed in collotype by Kunstanstalt Max Jaffé in Vienna, 13th Century., Illuminated; 29 cm
      Facsimile printed in 1965. Commentary volume included. This is the oldest surviving Ashkenazi illuminated Haggadah manuscript and gets its name from its illustrations of human figures with pronounced birds' heads. It is signed by a scribed named Menahem.
    - Die Darmstädter Pessach-Haggadah: codex orientalis 8 der Landesbibliothek zu Darmstadt aus dem vierzehnten jahrhundert / herausgegeben und erläutert von Bruno Italiener; unter mitwirkung von Aron Freimann, August L. Mayer und Adolf Schmidt; mit einer gesamtbibliographie der illustrierten Haggadah, 15th Century., Illuminated; 29-37 cm
      Facsimile published in Leipzig, Germany, 1927-28. Written by the scribe Israel ben Meir of Heidelberg. The illuminations reflect contemporary German architecture and dress.
    - The Ashkenazi Haggadah: a Hebrew manuscript of the mid-15th Century from the collections of the British Library / written and illuminated by Joel ben Simeon, called Feibusch Ashkenazi; with a commentary attributed to Eleazar ben Judah of Worms; introduction, notes on the illuminations, transcription, and English translation by David Goldstein, 16th Century., Illuminated; 39 cm
      Facsimile printed in Tel Aviv, 1985. Additional artwork added by a different artist. Includes a transcription of the Hebrew as well as an English translation.
    - The Ashkenazi Haggadah: a Hebrew manuscript of the mid-15th Century from the collections of the British Library / written and illuminated by Joel ben Simeon called Feibusch Ashkenazi; with a commentary attributed to Eleazar ben Judah of Worms; introduction, notes on the illumination, transcription, and English translation by David Goldstein, 16th Century., Illuminated; 39 cm
      Facsimile printed in New York, 1985. Additional artwork added by a different artist. Includes a transcription of the Hebrew as well as an English translation.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Ofenbakh 482 = The Passover Haggadah: Offenbach 1722, 1722., Illustrated; 32 cm
      Facsimile printed in Jerusalem in 1972. Originally published by Yisra'el ben Mosheh.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Ashkenaz, 489 (1729) = Pessach Haggadah: Ashkenaz, 1729., 1729., Illuminated; 31 cm
      Facsimile printed in Tel Aviv, 1985. Text in Hebrew; rubrics in Hebrew and Yiddish. Facsimile of Pessach Haggadah, –ttingen, 1729. Scribe and illustrator: Jacob ben Michael May Segal; introduction by Chaya Benjamin. Many of the illuminations are based on woodcuts and copper engravings from the printed Haggadot of Venice and Amsterdam.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Altona, Ashkenaz, 498 (1738) / katav ve-tsayar, Yosef ben David mi-Laypnik = Passover Haggadah: Altona, Germany, 1738 / scribe, illustrator Joseph ben David of Leipnik, 1738., Illustrated; 34 cm
      Facsimile published in Tel Aviv, 1987. Includes an abbreviation of the Zevah Pesah commentary by Isaac Abravanel as well as a short mystical commentary. Ashkenazi and Sephardi rites included. Includes a separate introduction in Hebrew and English.
    - Hagadat Kopenhagen 499: faksimilah = Copenhagen Haggadah: facsimile, 1739., Illuminated; 33 cm
      This facsimile was printed in Tel Aviv, 1986. The Artist: Uri Pheibush [Philip Isac Levy] ... Introduction by Chaya Benjamin (Hebrew and English, [12] p.) inserted.
    - Hagadah Seder shel Pesah, 1740-1741., Illustrated; 31 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / [`orekh u-mehkar, Nahman Ran, `orekhet mishneh, Nivah Penai] = Passover Haggadah / [editor and research, Nachman Ran, assist. editor, Niva Panai], 1751., Illustrated; 28 x 329 cmfolded to 28 x 12 cm
      Facsimile published in Tel Aviv, 1986. Facsimile of: The Altona-Hamburg Haggadah. Manuscript. 1751 (Codex Levy 22). English and Hebrew. Map of the Land of Israel, drawn by Abraham Bar-Yaacov, the first Hebrew-letter printed map, attached to the Amsterdam Haggadah from 1696--P. [27-30]. By the Scriber ... Uri Feivisch, son of Rabbi Itzhak Eizik ....
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / [`orekh u-mehkar, Nahman Ran, `orekhet mishneh, Nivah Penai] = Passover Haggadah / [editor and research, Nachman Ran, assist. editor, Niva Panai], 1751., Illustrated; 28 x 329 cmfolded to 28 x 12 cm
    - Passover Haggada: Germany, 1768 / scribe/illustrator, Nathan ben Abraham Speyer of Breslau; collection of the Jewish National and University Library, Jerusalem, Ms. Heb. 8vo 2340 = Hagadah shel Pesah: Ashkenaz, 528 (1768) / katav ve-tsiyer Natan ben Avraham Shpaiyer mi-Bresla; osef Bet ha-sefarim ha-le'umi veha-universita'i, Yerushalayim, ketav-yad 8vo 2340, 1768., Illuminated; 30 cm
      Facsimile published in Tel Aviv, 1984. Text in Hebrew, rubrics in Yiddish. Accompanied by introductory material in Hebrew and English, including bibliographies, prepared by Chaya Benjamin.
    - Hagadah Seder shel Pesah, 1782-1783., Text only; 31 cm
    - Hagadah shel pesah: ins daytsh, iberzetst und mit nittslikhen anmerkungn ferzehn, 1795., Illustrated; 17 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1795-1796., Text only; 17 cm
    - Ma'aleh bet horin, 1795-1796., Text only; 23 cm
      Stamped on first page: Auguste Steinert Berlin. Includes laws for Passover. Some of the text is underlined in pencil and a few marginal notes are written in pencil. Includes commentary by Abarbanel.
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, oder, Fortrag oyf dia beyden erzten abende Pesah, 1829., Text only; 17 cm
    - Seder Ha-Hagadah le-lel shemorim: meduyak hetiv u-mesudar yafe u-meturgam ashkenazit = Hagadah / me-et Volf ben Shimshon ben ish Haidenhaim, 1877., .; 18 cm
      Hebrew with Yiddish translation Hebrew signature of the publisher is found on the title page. [Missing from shelf.]
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1893., Text only; 20 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1904., Text only; 22 cm
    - Seder ha-Hagadah le-lel shimurim = Erzählung von dem Auszuge Israels aus „gypten... / übersetzt von W. Heidenheim .., 190-?., Illustrated; 21 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1910., Text only; 22 cm
    - Seder ha-Hagadah le-lel shimurim = Erzählung von dem Auszuge Israels aus „gypten für die beiden ersten Pessachabende / nach W. Heidenheim; neu übersetzt von Rabbiner Dr. Selig Bamberger, 1921., Text only; 25 cm
      Hebrew with German translation Limited ed. of 100 copies on handmade paper.
    - Hagada: aangeboden door de firma Wed. J. Stein, Amsterdam .., 1922., Text only; 23 cm
    - Haggadah shel Pesah, 1923., Illustrated; 27 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1927., Illustrated; 22 cm
    - Seder hagadah shel Pesah = Die Pessach-Haggada / herausgegeben und erklärt von E. D. Goldschmidt, 1937., Text only; 20 cm
    - Passover Seder service: Deutsches Theatre Restaurant, Munich, Germany, April 15-16, 1946 / conducting, Abraham J. Klausner, 1945-1946., Illustrated; 21 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 1947., Illustrated; 23 cm
      Printed and distributed in Germany by the American Joint Distribution Committee.
    - Pessach-Haggadah / bearbeitet von Robert Raphael Geis, 1954., Illustrated; 23 cm
  - India Subseries, 1918-1968, 1 item
    - Order of service for Passover (Haggada) / issued by the Jewish War Services Committee for India, 1918., Text only; 19 cm
  - Israel Subseries, 1899-2002, 122 items
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1930., Illustrated; 25 cm
    - Hagadah le-Pesah nusah ha-Rambam be-sifro ha-Yad ha-hazakah ...: `im biografiah ketsarah me-hayey ha-Rambam ... :`a.p. seder minhage ha-Gra mi-Vilna .., 1935., Illustrated; 23 cm
    - Hagadah Erets Yisre'elit le-Fesah, 1938., Illustrated; 18 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 1946., Illustrated; 22 cm
      Published by Kibbutz Hashomer Hatzair, the Kibbutz federation of a Zionist youth movement. Non-traditional text with some traditional elements. Duke has two copies of this haggadah. c.2 contains hand written and stamped ceremonial directions in Hebrew.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 1946., Illustrated; 24 cm
      The Duke catalog has a date of 1949, but the Hebrew date on the cover corresponds to 1946. Black and white drawings with first two pages colored in by hand. Non-Traditional text which reflects the secular leanings of the early kibbutz community.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 1946., Illustrated; 22 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah `al pi minhag Ashkenaz u-Sefarad / mugah u-mevo'ar `al yede Dani'el Goldschmidt, 1947., Text only; 22 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1948., Illustrated; 22 cm
    - Le-hag ha-herut 708, 1948., Illustrated; 24 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = Service for the first nights of Passover / with a revised English translation by Joseph Loewy and Joseph Guens, 1948., Illustrated; 25 cm
      Published before the independence of Israel. Includes music for a few songs at the end.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 194-?., Illustrated; 25 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 194-?., Illustrated; 27 cm
    - Aviv, 194-?., Illustrated; 21 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 194-?., Illustrated; 22 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 194-?., Illustrated; 24 cm
      Handwritten non-traditional text. P. 10 (Hebrew nos.) with stylized ill. of Hebrew slaves and of free Hebrews going out of Egypt carrying unleavened dough on their heads; p. 10 (Arabic nos.) shows full page ill. of ship off coast of mandate Palestine at night with illegal immigrants coming ashore.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah = Service for the first nights of Passover / with a revised English translation by Joseph Loewy and Joseph Guens, 1950., Illustrated; 25 cm
    - Seder shel Pesah nosah Yagur, 1951., Text only; 25 cm
    - Seder Hagadah shel Pesah, 1954., Text only; 17 cm
      Includes commentaries by Moses Sofer, Samuel Ehrenfeld and David Tsevi Ehrenfeld. This Haggadah is a reprint of the original which was published in Viena, 1883-1884.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: service for the first nights of Passover / 17 illustrations in colour by A. Allweil, an essay by Max Brod and an accompanying text by I.M. Lask; with a revised English translation and copious explanatory notes by Joseph Loewy and Joseph Guens, 1954., Illustrated; 27 cm
      Plates printed on separte paper and mounted on leaves.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1955., Illustrated; 28 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: `im mador meyuhad li-yeladim "Ve-higadeta le-vinkha" / `arukh `al yede Sh.S.; tiken, `iter ve-tsiyer Ts. Livni, 1955., Illustrated; 28 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: service for the first nights of Passover / with a revised English translation and copious explanatory notes by Joseph Loewy and Joseph Guens; with coloured illustrations, 1956., Illustrated; 32 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1958., Illustrated; 17 x 25 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1958., Illustrated; 92 mm x 13 cm
      Slip mounted on p. 4 of cover indicates Haggadah distributed to participants in Passover tour 4/22/59 to 5/3/59.
    - Samaritan Haggada and Pessah Passover: Zevah korban ha-Pesah, 1958., Text only; 24 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah., 1959., Text only; 17 cm
      Hebrew Only. A sticker with Hebrew writing on the back reveals that it was intended for the participants of a tour group celebrating passover from April 22 - May 3 1959.
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1960., Illustrated; 27 cm
    - Hagadah shelemah, 1960., Text only; 26 cm
    - Bibliografyah shel hagadot Pesah mi-reshit ha-defus ve-`ad ha-yom be-tseruf `esrim ve-hamishah tsilume dapim mi-tokh hagadot yikrot-metsi'ut, 1960., Illustrated; 35 cm
    - Bibliografyah shel hagadot Pesah mi-reshit ha-defus ve-`ad ha-yom be-tseruf `esrim ve-hamishah tsilume dapim mi-tokh hagadot yikrot-metsi'ut, 1960., Illustrated; 35 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1961., Illustrated; 28 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1961., Illustrated; 19 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1962., Illustrated; 23 cm
    - Ta`arukhat Hagadot-Pesh me-osfo R. Natan Stayner .., 1964., Illustrated; 17 cm
    - Hagadah, 1965., Illustrated; 24 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / targum angli hadash me-et Betsal'el Rot; `arikhah Beno Rotenberg; mavo Mikha'el Avi-Yonah = The Passover Haggadah / a new English version by Cecil Roth; edited by Beno Rothenberg; introduction by Michael Avi-Yonah, 1965., Illustrated; 31 cm
    - Haggada for Passover = Hagadah / published in enlarged Hebrew and English type for the partially sighted for the Women's Branch of the Union of Orthodox Jewish Congregations of America and the Jewish Braille Institute of America, Inc. ...; newly translated throughout, with an introduction, by Harold Fisch, 1967., Text only; 38 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Hagadat Yerushalayim / nikhtevah ve-tsuyerah bi-yede Shemu'el Boneh, 1968., Illuminated; 31 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah nikhtevah ve-tsuyerah be-Nikelsburg bi- shenat 508 = The Passover Haggadah written and illustrated in Nickelsburg 1748, 1973., Illustrated; 30 cm
    - Hagadah = Haggadah = Hagadat G'erusalem Post = The Jerusalem Post Haggadah / hukhnah bi-yede Shoshanah Voker, 1980., Illuminated; 28 cm
    - The Passover Haggadah / illustrated by Naftali Bezem; calligraphy by Moshe Mordechai Ben-Dov; designed by Elazar Gilad; translated by Ted William Gross, 1982., Illustrated; 34 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / tsiyer Naftali Bezem; katav Mosheh Mordekhai b.R. Yisaskhar Dov ben Dov, 1982., Illustrated; 42 cm
    - ha-Metsayer bi-yetsi'at Mitsrayim: Hagadot metsuyarot min ha-me'ah ha-18 / [mehkar ve-tekst, Havivah Peled-Karmeli; `arikhah, Yonah Fisher], 1983., Illustrated; 27 cm
    - The Passover Haggadah / commentary by Adin Steinsaltz, 1983., Illustrated; 25 cm
    - ha-Metsayer bi-yetsi'at Mitsrayim: Hagadot metsuyarot min ha-me'ah ha-18 / [mehkar ve-tekst, Havivah Peled-Karmeli; `arikhah, Yonah Fisher], 1983., Illustrated; 27 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah / metsuyeret bi-yede Aharon Shevo, 1984., Illustrated; 28 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah le-zekher ha-Sho`ah = Pessach Haggadah in memory of the Holocaust / illustrated by David Wander; calligraphy and micrography by Yonah Weinrib, 1985., Illustrated; 43 cm
    - The golden Haggadah of Jerusalem / illustration, Jossi Stern; calligraphy, Noah Ophir = Hagadat ha-zahav shel Yerushalayim / tsiyer Yosi Shtern; katav Noah Ofir, 1986., Illustrated; 25 x 34 cm
    - Hagadat Volakh: Hagadah shel Pesah le-zekher ha-Sho'ah = The Wolloch Haggadah: Pessach Haggadah in memory of the Holocaust / illustrated by David Wander; calligraphy and micrography by Yonah Weinrib, 1988., Illustrated; 28 cm
    - Hagadah shel Pesah: Hagadat ha-tefutsot / tsiyurim, Shelomoh Kats; targum le-Anglit, G'eremy Haiman = The Diaspora Haggadah: the artistic and transliterated Haggadah of Passover / paintings by Shlomo Katz; English translation by Jeremy Hyman, 1988., Illustrated; 34 cm
    - Hagadah shel hidur: Hagadah shel Pesah, 1989., Illustrated; 17 cm
    - 'Arba` hagadot = 4 haggadot: me-'osef Bet ha-sefarim ha-le'umi veha-universita'i bi-Yerushalayim, 1989., Illustrated; 26 x 37 x 3 cm